[音樂]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas：從生成將生成
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Write a from a function that produces a generator that will produce
一系列的值。
a series of values.
所以，我們要把一個零傳遞給FROM函式。
So, we're going to pass a zero to the from function.
它將返回一個生成器，在本例中我稱之為index。
It will return a generator in this case I'm calling it index.
每次我呼叫index時，它都會返回
Every time I call index, it will return the next value in
以起始值開始的序列。
the sequence that started with the starting value.
&gt；&gt；演講者2：什麼是發電機？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: What's a generator?
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：生成器是一個會製造東西的函式。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Generator is a function that will make things.
所以每次你打電話給發電機，你就會得到另一樣東西。
So each time you call a generator, you'll get another thing.
在這種情況下，你在製造一臺發電機，
In this case, where you were making a generator that's
將產生一個從某個值開始的整數序列。
gonna produce a sequences of integers starting at some value.
好的，這是來自，
Okay, so here is from,
FROM接受起始值，它返回一個計算下一個值的函式
from takes a start value it returns a function which computes the next value
只需開始，它就會在開始時新增一個，然後返回下一個。
simply by taking the start it adds one to start and then returns next.
那麼，誰有什麼管用的東西？
So, who got something that works?
好的，很好，有人採取了不同的方法嗎？
Okay, very good, anybody take a different approach?
&gt；&gt；演講者2：我剛剛在您的函式中看到了這一點。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I just read that in your function.
道格拉斯：好的，我剛剛退回了X加等於1。道格拉斯：好的。
I just did return X plus equals one &gt;&gt; Douglas: Okay
&gt；&gt；揚聲器2：可以嗎？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: That work?
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：當然可以。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Sure.
還有其他人嗎？
Anybody else?
&gt；&gt；演講者3：那會給你一個不同的起點。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: That will give you a starting point different.
那就應該是零開始了。
Then zero ought to be starting one.
道格拉斯：是的，他說得對。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Yeah, he's right.
&gt；&gt；揚聲器2：您會喜歡這個的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: You'll like this.
道格拉斯：是的，我確實退回了Start plus&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：是的，
I did return start plus plus &gt;&gt; Douglas: Yeah,
總會有這樣的事。
there's always one of those.
&gt；&gt；演講者3：[笑]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：還有人嗎？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: Anybody else?
&gt；&gt；揚聲器4：你想開始加一個嗎？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: You wanna get start plus one?
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：是的，從1開始，如果我們說從零開始，我們需要從零開始。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Yeah, start 1’s to be, if we say from zero we need to start from zero.
&gt；&gt；揚聲器4：你需要加，加1。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: You need plus, plus 1.
但是你返回加，加開始。
But you return plus, plus start.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：我們不會這麼做的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: We’re not doing that.
&gt；&gt；揚聲器3：是的，我知道你不會那麼做的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Yeah, I know you’re not doing that.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：好了，準備好繼續前進了嗎？
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Okay, ready to move on?
好的，這是下一個，寫一個to函式，它接受一個生成器，
Okay here's the next one, write a to function that takes a generator and
一個終結值，並返回一個生成器，該生成器將生成達到該限制的數字。
an end value and returns a generator that will produce numbers up to that limit.
因此，我們將傳遞給，以執行一個生成器，我們
So, we'll pass to the to function a generator that we
使用我們的FROM函式進行製作。
make with our from function.
所以我將從1傳遞到2，也傳遞給它3，
So I will pass from 1 to 2 and also pass it a 3, and
它將返回一個生成器，該生成器將返回值最高可達2，並且
it will return a generator which will return values up to the limit to 2 and
從這一點開始，它將返回UNDEFINED。
from that point on it will return undefined instead.
&gt；&gt；演講者2：那麼就之前的限制而言，這一限制不包括限制？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So on the previous limit, this one does not include the limit?
[聽不見]次。
[INAUDIBLE] times.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：對，這是2a值&gt；&gt；演講者2：不包括這個。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Right, this is 2 a value &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Not including this one.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：對。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Right.
&gt；&gt；[INAUDIBLE]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：嗯，
&gt;&gt; [INAUDIBLE] &gt;&gt; Douglas: Well,
這是我們語言中的慣例，對嗎？
this is the convention we have in our languages, right?
&gt；&gt；演講者4：沒錯。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: That's true.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：當你在服用某種亞型的時候？
&gt;&gt; Douglas: When you're taking a substrain of something?
這就是我們做這件事的方式。
This is the way we do it.
&gt；&gt；揚聲器4：這就是你的理由嗎，麥克斯？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Is this your reason Max?
道格拉斯：是的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Yeah.
[聲音]所以，這裡有一種編寫to函式的方法。
[SOUND] So, here's one way to write the to function.
要獲取一個生成器和一個終結值，
To takes a generator and an end value,
它返回一個函式，該函式從生成器獲取下一個值。
it returns a function that gets the next value from the generator.
如果該值小於結束值，則返回該值，
If that value is less than the end value, it returns that value,
否則，它將返回UNDEFINED。
otherwise it returns undefined.
那麼，誰有什麼管用的東西？
So, who got something that works?
非常好。
Very good.
有沒有人採取不同的方法或做一些令人驚歎的事情？
Anyone take a different approach or do something amazing?
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：精彩、壯觀，諸如此類。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Wonderful, spectacular, anything like that.
&gt；&gt；揚聲器2：太神奇了，但是我的看起來和極限函式非常相似。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Amazing it is but mine looks very similar to the limit function.
只是使用它內部的發電機。
Just uses from generators inside of it.
所以我在外部作用域中設定了變數，然後新增一個數字
So I set variable in the outer scope, and then add a number to that and
如果該數字小於或等於返回查詢限制，
if that number is less than or equal to the limit a return find,
否則就是發電機。
otherwise generator.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：好的，還有沒有人？
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Okay, anybody else?
好的，想再來一次嗎？
All right, wanna do another one?
好的，好的，我們再做一次。
Yes, all right, let's do another one.
好的，讓我們編寫一個生成生成器的FROM TO函式
Okay, let's write a from to function that produces a generator
在一定範圍內創造價值。
that produces value in a range.
所以我們將從0和3傳遞到0和3，它會讓我們得到生成器
So we're going to pass to fromTo 0 and 3 and it will get us the generator
這給了我們一個序列0，1，2，然後是未定義的。
that gives us a sequence zero, one, two and then undefined.
下面是返回中的FromTo、FromTo(Start，End)值
So here is fromto, fromto (start, end) value in the returns
呼叫的結果從(Start)傳遞到結束。
result of calling to passing it from (start), end.
那麼，誰有什麼管用的東西？
So, who got something that works?
非常好。
Very good.
誰做得更難？
Who did it the hard way?
是的，函數語言程式設計的第一條規則，
Yeah, first rule of functional programming,
讓函式來完成這項工作。
let the functions do the work.
編寫一個元素函式，該函式接受一個數組和一個生成器，並
Write an element function that takes an array and a generator and
返回將從陣列生成元素的生成器。
returns a generator that will produce elements from the array.
所以我們將傳遞給元素工廠，以及包含a、b、c和d的陣列。
So we're gonna pass to the element factory, and array containing a,b,c and d.
並將給它一個發電機，從2點1到3點，
And will give it a generator which does from two one to three,
這將給我們一個生成器，它將產生b和c，然後是未定義的。
and that will give us a generator which will produce b and c and then undefined.
這裡是元素，元素有一個數組和一個生成器。
So here's element, element takes an array and a generator.
它返回一個函式，該函式從生成器獲取下一個索引。
It returns a function that gets the next index from the generator.
如果索引不是未定義的，則它返回下一個索引，
If the index is not undefined it returns the next,
或該索引處的陣列元素。
or the element of the array at that index.
那麼，誰有什麼管用的東西？
So, who got something that works?
所以，我想談談這個帶下劃線的陳述。
So, I want to talk about this statement that's underlined.
因為如果你把它去掉，如果我們無條件地退貨，
Because if you leave that if out, if we do the return unconditionally,
它做的是同樣的事情。
it does the same thing.
它做同樣事情的原因有點奇怪。
And the reason it does the same thing is kind of weird.
所以,
So,
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：如果我們那裡沒有如果，
&gt;&gt; Douglas: If we don't have the if there,
如果索引是未定義的。
and if index is undefined.
則括號將變為未定義的字串。
Then the brackets will turn undefined into the string undefined.
然後它將查詢陣列中未定義的成員，並且找不到它，
It will then look for the member undefined in the array and not find it,
返回UNDEFINED，如果找不到什麼，就返回UNDEFINED。
and return undefined, which is what you return if you can't find something.
如果你省略了那個測試，它就會意外地起作用，除非在這種情況下
So it kind of accidentally works, if you leave that test out, except in the case
其中，如果有人在陣列中建立了未定義的屬性。
where if someone creates an undefined property in the array.
然後，它們可以使此函式的行為在這種情況下更改。
Then they can cause the behavior of this function to change in that case.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：那麼，您會在陣列中的節點上呼叫delete嗎？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So, you would to call delete on a node in the array?
&gt；&gt；Douglas：不，不刪除節點，如果您說陣列，那麼陣列叫什麼？
&gt;&gt; Douglas: No not deleting a node, if you said array, what are calling the array?
是的，如果我們說array.unfinition=5，
Yeah, if we said array.undefined = five,
則在這種情況下將返回5，而不是未定義
then in that case will return five instead of undefined
這可能不是你想要的，所以在大多數情況下它是有效的。
which might not be what you want, and so while most of the time it works.
我擔心的是那些讓你陷入困境的奇怪案件
I'm concerned about the weird cases which are what actually screw you up in
無論是在生產上還是在生活中。
production and at life.
因此，我寧願直截了當地尋找這種情況。
And so, I would rather be explicit and look for that case.
還有誰做了些不一樣的事嗎？
Anybody else do something different?
&gt；&gt；演講者2：我的意思是，這將繼續與任務相關。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: This is continued to be array, I mean, to the task.
道格拉斯：是的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Yeah.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 4：這裡是返回的陣列gen。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Here it's returned array gen.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：嗯-嗯，是的-&gt；&gt；揚聲器4：因為要做的事情太多了
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Mm-hm and yes- &gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Cuz there's too much to
那麼做吧。
do that.
[笑]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：幾乎總是在工作，
[LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: Almost always work,
修改元素函式，使生成器引數是可選的。
modify the element function so that the generator argument is optional.
如果沒有提供生成器，則
If the generator is not provided then each of the elements of
將提供陣列。
the array will be provided.
所以我們可以呼叫元素來傳遞陣列a、b、c和d，並且
So we can call element pass the array a, b, c, and d, and
我們將得到一個生成器，它將返回a、b、c、d和未定義。
we will get a generator which will return a, b, c, d and undefined.
這是修改後的元素，我所做的就是新增黃色方框中的程式碼。
So here is the revised element, all I did was add the code that's in the yellow box.
如果我們沒有通過發電機，我們也會打來電話
If we didn't get past a generator, then we'll call from too and
買一臺新的發電機，否則一切都一樣。
get a new generator, otherwise everything else is the same.
那麼，誰有什麼管用的東西？
So, who got something that works?
有沒有人試著用艱難的方式來做這件事？
Did anybody try to do it the hard way?
函式式程式設計的第一條規則。
First rule of functional programming.
是的，讓函式來做這件事。
Yeah, let functions do the work.
所以，我想談談我強調的條件。
So, I want to talk about the condition that I underlined.
我可以用三種方式寫下這句話。
There are three ways I could have written that.
這是我要顯式查詢的第一個函式，是否傳入了unfinition。
That's the first one where I'm looking for explicitly, did undefined get passed in.
也就是說什麼都沒傳進來。
Which means did nothing get passed in.
我可以寫的另一種方式是，性別的型別等於功能嗎？
Another way I could have written it is, is the type of gen equal to function?
所以如果他們傳入了一些東西，但這不是一個函式，
So if they passed in something but it wasn't a function,
我們會把它變成一個函式。
we'll make it a function.
所以這兩種方法的不同之處在於
So the difference between those two approaches is
第二個往往總是成功的，而且
the second one will tend to always succeed, and
如果傳入了一些不好的東西，第一個將傾向於失敗。
the first one will tend to fail if something bad was passed in.
這通常取決於您的應用程式的特性，
And it depends on the characteristics of your application generally,
快速失敗是您想要的，因為它可以幫助您更快地發現錯誤。
fast failure is what you want because it helps you discover bugs faster.
但有時您的程式碼非常關鍵，您需要確保
But sometimes you got code which is really critical, and you wanna be sure that
不管發生什麼，這個程式碼都會正常工作。
no matter what happens this code is gonna be working right.
第三種寫這種情況的方法是做一個看漲檢查。
The third way you could write that condition would be to do a bullish check.
如果不是GEN，那就做點什麼，我不喜歡那樣。
if not gen then do something and I don't like that.
因為我們在製造這種情況的過程中想要做的就是把整個
Because what we're trying to do in making the condition is divide the whole
可能的宇宙變成兩種狀態中的一種，要麼是，要麼不是。
universe of possibilities into one of two states that either is or it isn't.
看漲的案例以一種非常奇怪的方式將其分裂，
And the bullish case splits it in a really weird way in that,
如果他們打進一杆的話，行為會非常，
if they pass in a one, the behavior will be very,
與他們通過零的時候有很大的不同。
very different than if they passed in a zero.
在我看來，零分之一的人應該表現得如此不同，這對我來說是沒有意義的
And it doesn't make sense to me that one in zero should behave that differently
當我們在尋找函式時。
when we're looking for a function.
這就是為什麼我認為JavaScript依賴於布林值和
So this is why I think that JavaScript depending on boolish values and
條件是一個錯誤，我建議總是更明確。
conditions was a mistake, I recommend always be more explicit.
或者想一想，我是想要快速失敗的問題，還是
Either figure out, do I want the fast failure question or
我想要意志似乎總是成功的問題嗎，但是
do I want the will seem to always succeed question, but
不是方便的那個，它可以以意想不到的方式跨越這兩個方面。
not the the convenient one which can straddle both of those in unexpected ways.
嗯。
Yeah.
&gt；&gt；[INAUDIBLE]&gt；&gt；Douglas：在這種情況下，
&gt;&gt; [INAUDIBLE] &gt;&gt; Douglas: In that case,
那也會很好用的。
that'll work fine too.
我們會永遠走下去，但我們會跑到盡頭，發現事情是這樣的
From we'll keep going forever but we run into the end to find things so
它會停下來的，所以它自己也可以。
it'll stop so from by itself is also okay.
還有其他人嗎？
Anybody else?
&gt；&gt；揚聲器4：[聽不見]那個時候，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: [INAUDIBLE] That when,
因為你說過
because you said
未定義的，與之相對的
undefined, as opposed
去布林廣場。
to boole square.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：對。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Right.
所以，我過去推薦使用邏輯OR
So, I used to recommend using the logical OR
接線員去做你建議的事情。
operator to do something like you're suggesting.
替換預設值和
To replace default values and
我已經不推薦了，因為它太危險了。
I've stopped recommending that because it's too hazardous.
如果有人傳了個零，零就是錯誤的，所以
That if someone passes in a zero, zero is falsely and so
如果我們沒有預料到它會被替換的話，它可能會被替換。
it might get replaced in cases we don't expect it will.
這是有問題的，所以
And that's problematic so
我現在建議你應該明確一點，不要依賴粗魯的卡盤。
I now recommend instead be explicit don't depend on boolish chucks.